TODD F. BARTELT

toddfbartelt@gmail.com | 913-636-7276 | Lenexa, KS 66215 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/todd-bartelt Github: https://github.com/bartelto | Portfolio: https://toddbartelt.com

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 10+ years' experience in desktop software development and graphic design. Blends a creative knack with a sharp eye for detail in developing user-friendly applications. An insightful leader, dedicated to exceeding expectations while ensuring that the whole team crosses the finish line together.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, C++, VB.NET, SQL, MongoDB

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Redux, Node.js, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase

Applications: Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro X

Relevant Experience

Software Developer On Assignment with Robert Half Technology

12/2019 - present Blue Springs, MO

Using new technologies to replace an older web portal used by insurance agents to contract new subagents, order supplies, and check commission statistics.

Key Accomplishments:

- Collected project requirements and features and organized them into tasks using Monday.com.
- Started work as a solo developer, and on-boarded a second developer to the project when one was later added to the team.

Project Analyst AmerisourceBergen Corporation

1/2014 - 8/2017

Chesterbrook, PA

Collected and researched project requirements; recommended and designed software and process changes for warehouse management; tested new software solutions.

Key Accomplishments:

- Took the lead in understanding the new legal and technical requirements of a project to track individual items through the distribution network; became the team's go-to expert.
- Hand-picked by a vice president to research, using test and production data, a possible expansion of a manual sorting process at the company's national distribution center.

Software Engineer CI³ Integrators

9/2009 - 10/2013

Lenexa, KS

Programmed, configured, upgraded and maintained a variety of software products controlling surveillance, access control, and HVAC for multiple customers. Provided both on-site and remote support during new construction projects and while troubleshooting issues. *Key Accomplishments*:

- Integrated a major customer's surveillance and access control systems with a custom user interface developed in Microsoft Visual Studio (C#).
- Exuded a calm confidence and a can-do attitude when on site with customers, thereby forging a strong sense of trust with customers and managers alike.

Proiects

TrackMeet | https://github.com/kentarosmith/trackmeet | https://track-meet.herokuapp.com

- Created a full-stack application to manage meeting space reservations. Features SMS confirmations for reservations.
- Individual contribution: Designed the MongoDB database schema; implemented Firebase authentication; set up Redux for global state management; and created a page to display/delete the user's active reservations.
- Technologies used: React, Redux, Hooks, JavaScript, Reactstrap, MongoDB, Node, Express, React Big Calendar, Nexmo API (https://www.nexmo.com)

Game Spark | https://github.com/bartelto/project-2 | https://bartelto.github.io/project-2/

- Constructed a social media platform for table-top game enthusiasts. Enables each user to set
 up a profile specifying the game(s) that they are interested in playing and matches them to
 other users with the same interests.
- Individual contribution: Designed the MySQL database schema; created the Sequelize models to interface with the database; and wrote the HTML and API routes for the app's Node/Express server and most of the front-end AJAX calls to the server.
- *Technologies used*: JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MySQL, Node, Express, Board Game Atlas API (https://www.boardgameatlas.com)

War of Words | https://github.com/bartelto/project-1 | https://bartelto.github.io/project-1/

- Developed a two-player online version of the card game War. Includes an in-game chat feature with synthesized voice that players can use to hurl insults at each other.
- Individual contribution: Built a waiting-room style system for meeting other players and challenging them to games (using Firebase); designed the styling for the playing cards; created a chat system (using text and synthesized voice) and player-to-player coordination via Firebase.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap, Deck of Cards API (https://deckofcardsapi.com), Responsive Voice API (https://responsivevoice.org), Adorable Avatars API (https://avatars.adorable.io)

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Kansas, Overland Park, KS An intensive, 24-week program focused on building development skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js and React.

Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering: University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI

Bachelor of Arts - Mathematics and Physics: Luther College, Decorah, IA